# Athumani Kulindwa Web Developer | Data Analyst

## Profile

Experienced in Javascript, Python, SQL, HTML, CSS and Data visualization using Tableau. I have led the front end development of an android based healthcare app called Wired Mothers for The Ministry of Health of Zanzibar. Even though my most recent experience and official title is of the aviation industry, I mostly worked with data as a reliability engineer to identify trends and try to predict failures before they occur, saving time, money and resources using data analytics techniques and tools. With that being said, programming is my career of choice.

### Projects

### Responsive Personal Website

You are looking at it. This website serves as my portfolio. It includes my recent projects and work experience as well as my Education. As can be seen, my work experience is as diverse as my education. My official title however is; Web Developer.

O7HMAN

### Data Cleaning in SQL

In this project, Raw Nashville Housing Data was scanned for missing field data, addresses split into street address and city&state, removed duplicate values, identified wrongly entered values and updated with correct ones.

DATA CLEANING

### Data Exploration in SQL

This project involved the exploration of Covd-19 Data for key bits of information such as; the total number of Deaths per location population (Death Percentage), the Total number of cases per location

population (Infection Percentage), and many more.

#### DATA EXPLORATION

### Tableau Projects

This is a collection of Data visualization charts aimed at communicating the results of data exploration in a clearer and effective manner.

TABLEAU PROJECTS

## Work Experience

My complete work history is available on LinkedIn.

### Reliability Engineer

Air Tanzania Jan 2023 - Jan 2024

#### Key contributions:

- Analyzed data to identify trends, patterns, and potential failure points to create effective maintenance schedules that minimize downtime and maximize safety.
- collected and analyzed data from various sources, such as flight records, maintenance logs, and sensor readings, to identify potential issues or trends that could impact aircraft reliability using statistical methods and reliability analysis techniques.
- Collaborated with maintenance teams to develop proactive maintenance strategies that enhance asset reliability

### Technical Services Engineer | AD & SB

Air Tanzania Apr 2021 - Dec 2022

#### Key contributions:

- Prepared and issue the required technical documents in accordance with approved procedures and regulatory requirements.
- Guided the setup and installation process, ensured all systems and programs worked well together, and assisted with resolving any issues or conflicts.
- Performed weekly search for new, TCCA, EASA and FAA AD's applicable to Q400 fleet of aircrafts.

### Application Developer | Health Informatics Advisor

Tanzakesho

Dec 2013 - Dec 2016

Led the development of an android based healthcare app called Wired Mothers for Ministry of Health of Zanzibar.

#### Key contributions:

- · Responsible for setting code standards for the front-end development.
- · Provided ongoing onsite and remote user support for hospital and MoH staff.
- monitored its implementation by visiting various health facilities both in Unguja and Pemba.
- Created a fully customized front-end framework, including the UI/UX design and documentation.

### Skills

Javascript I Node.js I CSS I MSSQL I Tableau I Python

I React I Data analysis I Data visualization I Team leadership

I Project Coordination

### Education

### University of Maryland - College Park, Maryland

Certificate in Programming, 2015

Applications for Android handheld systems

- Android Platform and development environment
- Application Fundamentals and the activity class
- · Intents, Permissions and Fragments
- · User Interface Classes
- Threads and networking
- User notifications, Broadcast Receivers and Alarms
- Graphics, Touch and Multimedia
- Sensors, Location and Maps, and Data Management
- Build From scratch Assignment

### Kingston University - Kingston Upon Thames

Bachelor of Engineering with Honours, 2019

Aircraft Engineering

My final year project titled "Communication Optimization and Micro-managing Human Factors" aimed at increasing efficiency in Aircraft line maintenance as well as further reduce incidents that may occur as a result of human factors, consequently saving lives and reducing costs. *This project relied on communication between a fitness tracker and a mobile phone Application developed using React Native* to determine whether an engineer at any given time threatens the safety of the workplace

### Nílaí University - Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

Diploma in Engineering, 2016-2018

Aircraft Maintenance Engineering

Awarded a diploma in Air Craft Maintenance Engineering with a concentration in Avionics which also included 6 months of on job training.

© 2023 by Athumani Kulindwa I <u>07hman7@gmail.com</u>



